<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment | MSAIL</title>
    <link>https://MSAIL.github.io/tag/environment/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://MSAIL.github.io/tag/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Environment</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://MSAIL.github.io/media/logo.png</url>
      <title>Environment</title>
      <link>https://MSAIL.github.io/tag/environment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What could AI do for developing countries?</title>
      <link>https://MSAIL.github.io/post/developing_countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MSAIL.github.io/post/developing_countries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;10% of the world’s population lives in extreme poverty. This means that around 700 million people are living on less than $1.90 a day (1). And while $1.90 is the standard set by the World Bank defining the international poverty line (2), by no means does it imply that a person earning more than this amount has anywhere near suitable standards of living. Poorer populations in countries such as South Sudan, Bolivia, and India (2) still struggle to access basic features that are usually taken for granted in more developed countries, such as clean water, sanitation, education, and healthcare. 2.1 billion people in the world do not have access to safe drinking water (3). Around 1.8 billion people do not have access to adequate sanitation (4). And a report from the World Health Organization and the World Bank found that 400 million do not have access to essential health services (5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much work is already being undertaken in attempts to address these key issues, but more is still needed. Artificial intelligence (AI) is one such area where there is potential in alleviating some of the problems accompanying poverty. AI encompasses areas such as natural language processing and robotics, and has seen success in recent years with technology like autonomous vehicles, disease diagnosis, and recommendation algorithms. It is a powerful tool that also has the potential to be applied in ways beneficial to those dealing with the circumstances and living standards that typically go with poverty, especially in the realms of sanitation and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sanitation&#34;&gt;Sanitation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issues of sanitation for impoverished regions encompass topics such as lack of clean water, proper toilet systems, and waste management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One initiative attempting to address the problem of unsafe drinking water comes from an organization called Clean Water AI. Developers created a device that uses a “deep learning neural network to detect dangerous bacteria and harmful particles in water” (6). This technology employs computer vision to continuously monitor water quality and observe at a microscopic level. Widespread adoption of such an application could be beneficial for avoiding illnesses that arise from consumption of unsafe drinking water, such as cholera, typhoid, and polio (11).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a short video detailing what Clean Water AI does:

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Df1X1Km9riQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of proper waste management is another huge issue for underdeveloped regions. Without systems in place to take care of waste, it has become common for garbage to be thrown out in the surrounding areas or tossed into nearby water sources, where it sometimes becomes a playground for the neighboring children (7). While the establishment and utilization of governmental systems and resources could help manage this waste problem, there are also innovations in the AI sector that could be applied to target the problem. Recycling is an important process for these communities, and a robot designed by engineers from Simon Fraser University could help distinguish waste from recyclable materials (8). Growing company CleanRobotics is also taking steps to aid the waste management process with an autonomous system called TrashBot, which uses “robotics, computer vision and artificial intelligence to detect and separate landfill from recyclables” (12). Establishing automated systems for removing trash build-up could make the process easier in underdeveloped regions that lack the proper systems, and this could be crucial for lowering rates of disease caused by unhygienic environments. Such use of artificial intelligence could also potentially improve financial outlooks for the citizens in these areas through reuse and repurposing of recyclable materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;assembly_recycle.png&#34; alt=&#34;Recycling&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center style=&#34;font-size:15px;&#34;&gt;
Credit: Arvinder Singh
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard of education and the availability of educational resources also suffer in impoverished regions. Improved educational resources correlates positively with poverty statistics, as better education can benefit a region overall and positively impact its economy; “Education promotes economic growth because it provides skills that increase employment opportunities and income” (13)(14).  It is no surprise, then, that poorer regions have less access to proper education and fewer members of the community acquire an education. Lack of nearby schools, teachers, transportation, and time are all contributors to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal education is a popular initiative and there is work being done with the AI field to progress this goal. The rise of the internet has provided opportunities for bringing education into the home with the growing format of online schooling. Having the capability to view pre-taught lessons online is an important development in tackling the aforementioned impediments to education in underdeveloped regions. While there already exist many online resources that provide information on a variety of subjects for anyone to browse, language barriers still persist. The Presentation Translator from Microsoft is one such tool involving AI that is attempting to address language barriers (15). It uses speech recognition and translation to create subtitles of presentations in the desired language, which users can access through the tool’s affiliated app or browser. Google’s translation application can also be used for reading, writing, and speaking translations. There are many other recent developments in the field of natural language processing that can help tackle language barriers, and further expansion of available languages in these applications would be advantageous for poorer regions with lesser-known tongues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;translation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Learning&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center style=&#34;font-size:15px;&#34;&gt;
Credit: Arvinder Singh
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges-to-ai-access&#34;&gt;Challenges to AI Access&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much more growth happening in the AI field than what has been discussed here, and these technological advancements may be useful for targeting the persisting problems of poverty. But a major obstacle of using these tools to benefit developing countries is that many of these regions do not have the necessary structures in place to even implement such technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If specialists are needed for the establishment and maintenance of these AI applications, it is unlikely there will be someone in these areas who can fulfill that role, especially with the lack of access to education. It could become even more costly to hire outside help for maintaining these applications than it already is just to instate them. It must also be determined who will fund these tools – if the creators of these applications are not providing them for free, who will the responsibility fall upon for payment? The impoverished region presumably cannot bear that burden. Governmental assistance is often what is needed in these situations, but these are developing areas and governmental instability is a common feature, as well as the fact that the developing economy often does not yet supply the financial resources needed to establish such systems. Lack of internet access is another deterrent to providing these AI tools. When the poorer regions of Asia and Africa are the ones more likely to have fewer people using the internet (16), and less than 5% of people are online in the poorest countries (10), this creates difficulty in making use of resources such as online education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some initiatives seeking to resolve these obstacles are in the works, but they encounter their own obstacles in the sheer size of the issue and lack of financial resources (like Project Loon, which was attempting to provide worldwide internet access through essential parts of cell towers attached to balloons (10) but has since shut down in January of 2021, stating they “haven’t found a way to get the costs low enough to build a long-term, sustainable business” (17)). The barriers to technological access in underdeveloped areas are widespread and persistent, and it is difficult for one well-meaning company or organization to solve them. These significant concerns will need to be addressed if artificial intelligence is to play a role in reducing poverty in our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lifewater.org/blog/9-world-poverty-statistics-to-know-today/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;World Poverty Statistics via lifewater.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org/en/topic/poverty#:~:text=Today%2C%20less%20than%2010%20percent,less%20than%20%241.90%20a%20day.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;World Bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/water-access&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Water Access Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/healthywater/global/wash_statistics.html#:~:text=An%20estimated%20790%20million%20people,to%20an%20improved%20water%20supply.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CDC Wash Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/mediacentre/news/releases/2015/uhc-report/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New report shows that 400 million do not have access to essential health services via WHO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cleanwaterai.com/#intro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Clean Water AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pbs.org/newshour/world/in-worlds-poorest-slums-landfills-and-polluted-rivers-become-a-childs-playground&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;via PBS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[8]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sfu.ca/sfunews/stories/2019/07/artificial-intelligence-robot-reduces-waste-contamination-at-sfu.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Artificial intelligence robot reduces waste contamination at SFU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://loon.com/technology/flight-systems/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Flight systems via Loon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[10]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ourworldindata.org/internet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Internet Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/drinking-water#:~:text=Contaminated%20water%20can%20transmit%20diseases,000%20diarrhoeal%20deaths%20each%20year&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Contaminated water can transmit diseases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cleanrobotics.com/trashbot/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TrashBot via CleanRobotics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[13]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.globalcitizen.org/en/content/poverty-education-satistics-facts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Poverty Education Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[14]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/blog/2017/06/millions-could-escape-poverty-by-finishing-secondary-education-says-un-cultural-agency/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Millions could escape poverty by finishing secondary education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[15]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/translator/APPS/PRESENTATION-TRANSLATOR/#:~:text=About%20Presentation%20Translator,-Presentation%20Translator%20subtitles&amp;amp;text=As%20you%20speak%2C%20Presentation%20Translator,deaf%20or%20hard%20of%20hearing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Microsoft Presentation Translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[16]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pewresearch.org/global/2016/02/22/internet-access-growing-worldwide-but-remains-higher-in-advanced-economies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Internet access growing worldwide but remains higher in advanced economies via Pew Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[17]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/loon-for-all/loon-draft-c3fcebc11f3f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Loon for all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting the environment with AI</title>
      <link>https://MSAIL.github.io/post/ai_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://MSAIL.github.io/post/ai_environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Employing forest guards to protect endangered species. Organising volunteers for beach cleanups. Encouraging people to lead greener lifestyles. These are just some of the traditional methods that have been used to protect our environment. But, as Alan Turing once said, &amp;lsquo;At some stage,&amp;hellip; we should have to expect the machines to take control&amp;rsquo; [1] and this couldn’t be more true in these conservation efforts. Be it preserving wildlife, cleaning up the environment or reducing green-house gas emissions, AI has started playing an increasingly dominant role as it has become good at numerous tasks such as visually identifying and tracking poachers or designing the most energy efficient buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, for example, has used AI to increase the efficiency and significantly reduce the carbon footprint of its data centers. Data centers are massive energy consumers, being turned on 24/7 and requiring significant cooling. In 2016  it was reported that data centers used more electricity than Britain, producing roughly the same carbon footprint as the aviation industry [2]. A google search of the video &amp;ldquo;Despacito&amp;rdquo; activates six to eight of Google&amp;rsquo;s data centers [3]. In line with Google’s effort to stay carbon neutral (which they achieved in 2007 [3]), Google implemented a reinforcement learning algorithm in 2016 to determine what “cooling configurations (in its data centers) would reduce energy consumption” [5]. A reinforcement algorithm is a subset of machine learning in which the environment sends a ‘state’ and ‘reward’ to the ‘agent’ - the reinforcement learning algorithm - which in turn tries to maximise the reward [4]. The data centers using this reinforcement algorithm now consistently use 30% less energy than expected [6].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;data-center.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A Google Data Center in Iowa&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;font-size:15px;&#34;&gt;
A Google data center in Iowa (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/2018/08/17/140987/google-just-gave-control-over-data-center-cooling-to-an-ai/&#34;&gt;MIT Technology Review&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big companies are not the only ones that are taking advantage of AI to be more environmentally friendly. Small startups are using AI to tackle environmental problems as well. In a remote reserve in Ecuador, Topher White - founder of Rainforest connection (a startup that aims to combat deforestation) - climbs a tree using a small harness and installs a small box containing an old cell phone and solar cells [7]. These phones recoprd the natural rainforest sounds and use AI to detect logging noises, upon which a notification is sent to a ranger. He had started his firm after learning of the severity of deforestation: the number of trees has fallen by almost 50% since the beginning of human civilisation, and still over 15 billion trees are currently cut down every year [8]. Topher White&amp;rsquo;s first encounter with deforestation came ironically when he was on a trip to the rainforests of Borneo and was shocked to find illegal loggers just a hundred meters from the ranger station. Monitoring forests using AI to identify deforestation on satellite imagery often comes too late as satellite imagery requires some amount of deforestation before it becomes visible. However, the sound, he recalls, was deafening, which gave him the idea to mount these small phones on the treetops to identify logging. The very next day after the first installation, a logger was apprehended, and it is now preventing deforestation in 10 countries [7].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;topher-white.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Topher White&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;font-size:15px;&#34;&gt;
Topher White (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90435386/this-network-of-microphones-listens-for-the-chainsaws-of-illegal-loggers-in-the-rainforest&#34;&gt;Rolex/Stefan Walter via FastCompany&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;In fact even industries have turned to using AI to reduce costs and also increase their sustainability. One example is in Norway, where AI is being used to increase the efficiency of salmon farms [9]. Telenor Research - the research wing of the Norwegian telecoms company Telenor that is conducting research on the use of AI in fish farms - has come up with a neural network that uses a video feed from underwater cameras to determine when the salmon have finished feeding. The salmon swim in schools which disperse when food is thrown, but when the salmon are full, there are tiny deviations in this behaviour which the neural network picks up with 80% accuracy. Identifying these cues to better feed the right amount of food is beneficial economically (40% of the cost of salmon farms comes from fish food), and also helps prevent low oxygen levels, algae blooms and high nitrate levels which are toxic to fish, among other problems [12].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous other AI applications in this area: IBM has come up with a machine learning tool named AquaCloud to predict lice outbreaks in Salmon with 70% accuracy using a random forest algorithm [10]. The industries&amp;rsquo; increasingly intensive salmon and rainbow trout fishing encourages lice growth, which in turn makes them unsellable because lice feed on salmon skin [9].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;graph.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AquaCloud lice predictions&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;font-size:15px;&#34;&gt;
The results of AquaCloud: the green line shows the lice outbreak predicted two weeks in advance. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibm.com/blogs/cloud-computing/2018/09/17/data-science-norway-fish-farmers/&#34;&gt;NCE Seafood Innovation Center&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of AI on fish farms is especially beneficial as fish farms are sustainable and help to reduce the dependency on precious ocean fish populations. Wild salmon are being depleted at an alarming rate, yet Norway’s salmon exports are only rising. Even here, AI is also being used to track the wild salmon population in efforts to sustain its population [9].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These examples are but a small subset of AI-related projects that have been done. A brief search of new competitions regarding environmental solutions (most of which use AI, even if the competition implies only a possible technological solution), confirms the increasing interest in sustainability. The Xprize - a nonprofit that runs public competitions -  is currently running a $10 million prize rainforest competition to “develop novel technologies to rapidly and comprehensively survey rainforest biodiversity and use that data to improve our understanding of this complex ecosystem” [11]. Microsoft’s AI for Good grants are given to projects that enhance climate, water, and biodiversity. Prince William recently launched the Earthshot prize - a series of annual one million pound prize competitions in five categories such as reviving the oceans, cleaning the air, and protecting nature. There are countless other competitions and the examples discussed in this article are just a taste of the AI environmental projects to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://analyticsindiamag.com/ten-famous-quotes-about-artificial-intelligence/#:~:text=%E2%80%9CArtificial%20intelligence%20will%20reach%20human,%E2%80%93%20a%20billion%2Dfold.%E2%80%9D&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ten Famous Quotes about Artificial Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2]:

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3431148/why-data-centres-are-the-new-frontier-in-the-fight-against-climate-change.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Why Data Centres are the New Frontier in the Fight Against Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3]:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fortune.com/2019/09/18/internet-cloud-server-data-center-energy-consumption-renewable-coal/#:~:text=Data%20centers%20contribute%200.3%25%20to,one%20for%20every%20100%20Americans&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Internet Cloud has a Dirty Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4]:

&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/introduction-to-various-reinforcement-learning-algorithms-i-q-learning-sarsa-dqn-ddpg-72a5e0cb6287&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Introduction to Various Reinforcement Learning Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[5]:

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.technologyreview.com/2018/08/17/140987/google-just-gave-control-over-data-center-cooling-to-an-ai/#:~:text=Google%20revealed%20today%20that%20it,order%20to%20lower%20power%20consumption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Just Gave Control Over Data Center Cooling to an AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[6]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://services.google.com/fh/files/misc/google_2019-environmental-report.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google 2019 Environmental Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[7]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/90435386/this-network-of-microphones-listens-for-the-chainsaws-of-illegal-loggers-in-the-rainforest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This Network of Microphones Listens for the Chainsaws of Illegal Loggers in the Rainforest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[8]:

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature14967.epdf?sharing_token=662fd6kwyoW2pWYP7gTtqdRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0PVqBqhRh-xvvJTzHFUU9TMfiseqc7XBtw3yJeJCBwHMEd325JNCYv-3DvRroRPJJJkTX95golfBeN0XF1aaW8P59jvn5Sk0G_AU4O4V7AYAm5mOs3rWaxWrsHFRlurXF8zdFAS7FkVY9jYIW5ojMN-nvvGu0eucnWzPgZF2qvs0ca--T3nUj6njgtSI9LJcUU%3D&amp;amp;tracking_referrer=www.nationalgeographic.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Crowther et al., Mapping tree density at a global scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[9]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/ai-could-help-find-cheaper-and-smarter-ways-to-raise-fish-11601458200?mod=djemfoe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AI Could Help Find Cheaper and Smarter Ways to Raise Fish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[10]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibm.com/case-studies/the-seafood-innovation-cluster-hybrid-cloud-fish-farming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Seafood Innovation Cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[11]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rainforest.xprize.org/prizes/rainforest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Rainforest XPrize&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12]: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.petcoach.co/article/why-overfeeding-fish-is-a-problem-and-how-to-avoid-it/#:~:text=Accumulated%20uneaten%20food%20and%20fish,changes%20in%20the%20water%20chemistry.&amp;amp;text=High%20ammonia%20and%20nitrites%20%2D%20The,are%20extremely%20toxic%20to%20fish&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Why overfeeding fish is a problem and how to avoid it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
